Dammam, Saudi Arabia

osamaalsehl@gmail.com

0545714255

CAREER OBJECTIVE

Professional Civil Engineer with over experience in Project Management. Collaborate effectively with all project stakeholders to deliver sustainable built facilities that meet clients' expectations. Also offering an excellent blend of technical aptitude and creative ability. Expertise includes contract management, and the preparation and review of complex construction data, reports, and documents, including cost estimates, specifications, test results, and schedules. To continue professional development and expand design capabilities as a Civil Engineer while focusing on a career path in Project Development and Management.

EXPERIENCE

Civil Engineer

TÜV SÜD company

Nov 2022 to Present

- Implementation of quality control measures in building construction based on local regulations.
- Description and assessment of technical problems and development of proposed solutions.
- Monitoring and implementation of acceptances.
- Participation and performance of construction site visits include defect and deviation detection.
- Objective preparation of expert opinions for the assessment of claims for defects and damage from a technical point of view.
- Competent support of customers and moderation between business partners.

Facilities & Maintenance Engineer

Mar 2020 to Nov 2022

Shibh Al-Jazira Contracting company

- •Initiating the annual plan for the planned preventive maintenance, including predictive and pro-active maintenance. In addition to the
- preparation for all possible reactive maintenance.
- Full spare parts supply chain process from preparing the demanded parts, getting quotations, technical evaluations, purchase requests and orders.
- Supervision of contractor audits, performance, and ensure and compliance with the contract.
- Reporting the existing safety, and operation risks, mitigate the situation, and recommending a possible solution.

Project Engineer

Mar 2019 to Feb 2020

Shibh Al-Jazira Contracting company

- Developing project scopes and objectives, involving all relevant stakeholders and ensuring technical feasibility.
- Lead project planning workshops with the project team to obtain the required information for schedule development.

- Reviewing the planning and scheduling of work on current projects to ensure that activities are effectively planned, resourced, and completed.
- Project Planning experience and to be able to demonstrate relevant experience of project planning and schedule development for the delivery.
- I was project engineer to the project includes 50 villas.

Civil Engineer May 2018 to Feb 2019

Shibh Al-Jazira Contracting company

- Make the necessary Statement. and Progress Reports.
- Take the Samples. and Work according to schedules.
- Perform other duties related as necessary contractors invoices.
- Meeting with authorities, contractors and consults. Or assigned.
- Reviewing and approving of contractors invoices.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Civil Engineering

Jan 2018

Qassim University

Training & Certifications

- PMP PREPARATION COURSE.
- OSHA in the field of construction and industrial construction.
- QHSE from SAJCO.
- Management and follow-up of operation and maintenance contracts.
- Introduction to cyber security.
- Managing psychological stress in the work environment.
- Management excellence.
- Traffic safety materials and works and traffic limitation.
- Training program for traffic and safety engineers.

SKILLS

Civil Engineering	Civil 3D	• Analysis
 Technical 	Drainage	 Steel Manufacturing
 AutoCAD 	 Collaboration 	ABET
 Communication Skills 	Innovation	 SCE Associate
 Project Management 	 Concrete Work 	 Microsoft Excel

LANGUAGES

Arabic, Native

English, Professional